teachengineering.org 2018-10-04

# Privacy Policy - TeachEngineering

#### _TeachEngineering_ Privacy Statement

_TeachEngineering_ is committed to respecting the privacy of those who visit our web sites, and those who choose to subscribe or register for information, services, _TeachEngineering_ activities, or _TeachEngineering_ events. We have created this privacy policy to demonstrate our commitment to respect that privacy. Please review the _TeachEngineering_ Privacy Policy set forth below so that you can understand your options in using the _TeachEngineering_ web site or service. 

#### What this Privacy Covers

This privacy policy covers our treatment of personally identifiable information (e.g. first and last names, email address, a home or physical address, a telephone number, institution or affiliation) that _TeachEngineering_ may hold. You can visit any _TeachEngineering_ web site without identifying who you are, or revealing personally identifiable information. 

Any personally identifiable information _TeachEngineering_ obtains about a user of its web sites, services, search systems, events, or activities is information supplied voluntarily by the user as part of using the _TeachEngineering_ web site, or signing up for a particular service, activity or event, or in requesting information from _TeachEngineering_. 

_TeachEngineering_ is not responsible for the privacy practices of non _TeachEngineering_ web sites, services or organizations to which a _TeachEngineering_ web site, document or service may link, refer, or recommend. 

#### Sharing Information

At this time, _TeachEngineering_ uses the personal information that you provide in order to record and support your activities within _TeachEngineering_ web sites and web-based services, to provide you information about _TeachEngineering_ and related activities or events, and support your participation in activities and events. _TeachEngineering_ does not sell, rent, or share any personal information that it collects on its web sites or web-based services, or in organizing any activity or event. _TeachEngineering_ reserves the right, however, to change this policy, and will give you sufficient notice prior to doing so to allow you to "opt-in" to having your information shared. 

Personal information about _TeachEngineering_ members and users may, from time to time, be shared with outside contractors, auditors, consultants, collaborators, and others contracted by _TeachEngineering_ to assist in carrying out financial or operational activities. _TeachEngineering_ informs recipients of information about safeguarding personal information, and requires them to use it only for an authorized purpose consistent with this privacy policy, and to return it or destroy it upon completion of the activity. 

_TeachEngineering_ will disclose your personal information if required to do so by law or in the good-faith belief that such action is necessary to conform to the edicts of the law or comply with legal processes served to you, _TeachEngineering_ , or the site. 

#### General Use of Web Sites and Services

_TeachEngineering_ web sites and _TeachEngineering_ search and discovery systems maintain both raw log files and an organized database of documents retrieved and search queries entered. Information extracted from these log files (e.g., the pages requested, referral URLs, estimation of time spent on a page, estimation of a user session, result sets from search queries) is processed in aggregate to help _TeachEngineering_ gauge the effectiveness of its web sites and services, improve the performance and structure of its web sites and services, and for generating general use statistics. _TeachEngineering_ may share this type of information with its collaborators, sponsors and contractors to evaluate and improve the site and may publish these aggregate data as the result of academic research. 

#### Persistent Identifiers

In order to use some _TeachEngineering_ services, a user may be required to have a persistent identifier (e.g. a login identifier.) These identifiers may link to personally identifiable information the user supplies _TeachEngineering_ as part of registering or signing up for a service. These identifiers will not be linked to general use information except where the user has explicitly agreed to this action when signing up for the service (and where it may be a requirement to use the service) or when a user has volunteered to participate in an evaluation study of library collection use. 

#### IP Numbers and Domain Names

IP numbers and domain names are included in both the raw log files and the organized database and are used in helping to compute aggregate statistics (e.g., as a basis for defining a use session.) These IP numbers are not used to link _TeachEngineering_ use to any other personally identifiable information that _TeachEngineering_ may hold. 

#### Cookies

A _TeachEngineering_ web site or service may use cookies to improve the user's interaction with the site or service. _TeachEngineering_ does not use cookies to track visitors except in conjunction with a service that requires keeping track of a user's sessions, or actions, (e.g., a service allowing a user to see a history of their previous search queries). 

TeachEngineering utilizes the services of AddThis to facilitate sharing of TeachEngineering content. AddThis collects data about how content is shared and where those shares are occurring. You can opt-out of the AddThis data collection at: [ http://www.addthis.com/privacy/opt-out ](http://www.addthis.com/privacy/opt-out) The full privacy policy of AddThis is found at: [ http://www.addthis.com/privacy/privacy-policy](http://www.addthis.com/privacy/privacy-policy)

#### Public Forums: Email Lists, Chat Services, Web Forums

_TeachEngineering_ hosts and maintains publicly viewable curriculum reviews and suggestions for curriculum improvements submitted by its users. Users should note that that any information they post as a review or as a suggestion for curriculum improvement is available to all persons accessing _TeachEngineering_. 

#### Guidelines for Use by Children

Students are advised to consult with their parents or teachers before registering for any service or giving any personal information online. 

#### Inquiries

If you have questions about this privacy statement or the practices of _TeachEngineering_ , please contact [teachengineering@lists.colorado.edu](mailto:teachengineering@lists.colorado.edu) or write _TeachEngineering_ at the address below. Please include your name, address and email address when you contact us. 

_TeachEngineering_  
c/o Integrated Teaching and Learning Program  
522 UCB  
Boulder, CO 80309-0522
